Washingtoniana Slide Collection P026 P026
Test
Washingtoniana Slide Collection
1820-1987
Test
P026
8 boxes
Custodial History
These were assembled from a variety of locations throughout Washingtoniana and each series has a different donor. For Series 1 there is no deed of gift and it is uncertain as to how the library acquired the majority of these slides. A few images do note photographer but it is uncertain if they donated the images. Martin Mooney donated series 2 in 1995. Series 3 came to the library in 1996 as a gift of Lori Federman and Roy Watson donated series 4 circa 1990.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 217 slides assembled from various locations throughout the division. The images range from circa 1820 thru 1987 and cover a wide array of subjects. The topics include the Cherry Blossom Parade, Moscow Circus bears, Papal visit, federal buildings, street scenes, 1968 riots, Georgetown, urban planning and construction.
Neighborhoods; Photographs
- Series 1: Historic Image Collection
  Scope and Contents
  In addition to twenty-one slides of various Washington, DC buildings and street scenes there are twenty-six images of Georgetown, nineteen of the development at 11th and G Street, NW, twenty-six of Union Station, nineteen illustrating the construction of the H Street bridge, thirteen of the crash of a police helicopter on the 700 block of Yuma Street, SE, and twenty-five showing the aftermath of the 1968 riots.
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Potomac Boat Club (3530 Water Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 1)
      View of the Potomac Boat Club from Water Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3304 M Street at 34th Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 2)
      View of M Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Masonic Lodge (1000 block of Thomas Jefferson Street), 1973 January (Item 3)
      View of 1058-1068 Jefferson Street which includes a Masonic lodge and row houses (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (2900 block of M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 4)
      View of the intersection of M Street and 29th Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (2800 block of M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 5)
      View of row houses along the 2800 block of M Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (2910-2934 M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 6)
      View of the row houses between 2910 and 2934 M Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Cherry Hill Lane (Cherry Hill Lane), 1973 January (Item 7)
      View of the east side of Cherry Hill Lane (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3056-3072 M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 8)
      View of M Street between Thomas Jefferson and 31st Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3100-3150 M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 9)
      View of stores along M Street between 31st Street and Wisconsin Avenue (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Georgetown Houses (34th and Canal Streets), 1973 January (Item 10)
      View of the row houses at 34th and Canal Streets (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Georgetown Houses (1068 and 1070 30th Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 11)
      View of 1068 and 1070 30th Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - 31st Street - Georgetown (31st Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 12)
      View of the east side of 31st Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - 31st Street - Georgetown (31st Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 13)
      View of rainbow colored row houses along the east side of 31st Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Thomas Jefferson Street - Georgetown (Thomas Jefferson Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 14)
      View of the east side of Thomas Jefferson Street (1057 to the corner) in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3126-3150 M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 15)
      View of stores, 3126-3150, along M Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Cherry Hill Lane (Cherry Hill Lane), 1973 January (Item 16)
      looking east at houses on Cherry Hill Lane (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Wisconsin Avenue (1069-1081 Wisconsin Avenue), 1973 January (Item 17)
      Stores along Wisconsin Avenue between Canal and M Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Birch Funeral Home (Corner of M Street and Thomas Jefferson Street), 1973 January (Item 18)
      View of the Birch Funeral Home and Stable on the corner of M Street and Thomas Jefferson in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (2900 block M Street), 1973 January (Item 19)
      View of M Street, NW at 29th Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Bomford Mill (3261K Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 20)
      View of Bomford Mill (Photographer: Unknown)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3216 M Street), 1973 January (Item 21)
      View of houses along M Street looking toward Wisconsin Avenue (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Street ( Georgetown Street), 1973 January (Item 22)
      View of a river rock paved street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3278-3288 M Street), 1973 January (Item 23)
      View of stores along M Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Bomford Mill (K Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 24)
      View of the back of Bomford Mill at K Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - M Street - Georgetown (3118-3128 M Street, NW), 1973 January (Item 25)
      View of stores (3118-3128) along M Street in Georgetown (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Potomac Street - Georgetown (Potomac Street), 1973 January (Item 26)
      View of Potomac Street taken from Grace Street looking toward the Potomac River (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Street Scene, 1971 November (Item 27)
      View of a typical DC Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Street Scene, 1971 November (Item 28)
    - DC House, 1972 January (Item 29)
      View of row houses in DC (Photographer: Unknown)
    - White House (1600 Pennsylvania Avenue), Ca. 1820 (Item 30)
      Sketch of the White House from the Potomac River (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Northwest Map (Northwest), Ca. 1975 (Item 31)
      Map of a section of Northwest Washington with color coded buildings. Area King Library and Convention Center (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Proposed Plan (1000 block between G and H Streets, NW), Ca. 1975 (Item 32)
      Proposed plan for northwest Washington area (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Model (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 33)
      Close-up view of an architectural model (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Model (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 34)
    - Architectural Plan (H Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 35)
      Architectural plan for development on H Street near convention center (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Plan (G Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 36)
      Architectural plan for development on G Street near King Library (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Palais Royal Building (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca.1900 (Item 37)
      View of the Palais Royal department store building (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Woodward and Lothrop Building (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1980 (Item 38)
      View of the Woodies "North Building" once the home of Palais Royal (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Model (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 39)
      Architectural model of proposed development on G Street at 11th Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Site Plan (1000 block between G and H Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 40)
      Site plan for proposed development on 11th street between G and H Streets, NW (Photographer: Unknown)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Building Section plan (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 41)
      Drawing of a building cross section for proposed Palais Royal building site (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Building Plan (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 42)
      Plan for the development of the Palais Royal building site (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Model (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 43)
      Architectural model of proposed development on G Street at 11th Street, NW (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Model (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 44)
      Close-up view of the architectural model for proposed development on G Street at 11th (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Mclachlen Building (10th and G Streets, NW), 1984 April (Item 45)
      View of the Mclachlen building from G Street, NW (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Palais Royal Building (G and 11th Streets, NW), 1984 April (Item 46)
      Close-up of some architectural details on the Palais Royal building (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Architectural Model (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 47)
      Close-up view of architectural model for proposed development on G Street at 11th street, NW (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Building Plan section (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 48)
      Plan for the development of the Palais Royal building site (Photographer: RTKL Associates, Inc)
    - Building Plan (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 49)
      Architectural plan for the development of the Palais Royal building site (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Building Plan (G Street at 11th Street, NW), Ca. 1987 (Item 50)
    - Union Station Statue (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 51)
      Drawing of one of the statues on Union Station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station Model (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 52)
      Architectural model of Union Station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station Statues (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 53)
      Drawing of two of the statues on Union Station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 54)
      Drawing of the interior of the Union Station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station Model (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 55)
      Architectural model of the interior of Union Station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 56)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 57)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 58)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 59)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 60)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Union Station model (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 61)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 62)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 63)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 64)
    - Union Station interior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 65)
    - Union Station exterior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 66)
      Drawing of the exterior of the Union Station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station exterior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 67)
    - Union Station exterior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 68)
    - Locomotive Painting, 1987 March 5 (Item 69)
      Painting of Erie Railway steam engine "New York" with people standing near it - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Hornellsville Station Painting, 1987 March 5 (Item 70)
      Painting of Hornellsville Station with two locomotives and several cars - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Steam Locomotive, 1987 March 5 (Item 71)
      Painting of a Locomotive with passenger cars traveling near river with steamboat in the river - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Locomotive, 1987 March 5 (Item 72)
      Image of a locomotive - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Painting, 1987 March 5 (Item 73)
      Painting of people in a train station - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Locomotive, 1987 March 5 (Item 74)
      Image of a Locomotive steaming along the tracks - Image from HPRB Meeting (Photographer: Benjamin Thompson and Associates)
    - Union Station Statue (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 75)
    - Union Station model (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 76)
    - Union Station exterior (40 Massachusetts Avenue), 1987 March 5 (Item 77)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1975 November 10 (Item 78)
      Aerial view of the construction of the H Street bridge near Union Station (Photographer: M. C. Mooney)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 January 7 (Item 79)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 June 30 (Item 80)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - H Street Bridge (H Street, NE), 1977 July 5 (Item 81)
      Aerial view of the H Street bridge on opening day (Photographer: M. C. Mooney)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1975 November 10 (Item 82)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1975 November 10 (Item 83)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1975 November 10 (Item 84)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1975 November 10 (Item 85)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 January 7 (Item 86)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 January 7 (Item 87)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 January 7 (Item 88)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 January 7 (Item 89)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 June 30 (Item 90)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 June 30 (Item 91)
    - H Street Bridge Construction (H Street, NE), 1976 June 30 (Item 92)
    - H Street Bridge (H Street, NE), 1977 July 5 (Item 93)
    - H Street Bridge (H Street, NE), 1977 July 5 (Item 94)
    - H Street Bridge (H Street, NE), 1977 July 5 (Item 95)
    - H Street Bridge (H Street, NE), 1977 July 5 (Item 96)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 97)
      View of a Police helicopter crash near Ferebee-Hope Elementary School (Photographer: M. C. Mooney)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 98)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 99)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 100)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 101)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 102)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 103)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 104)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 105)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 106)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 107)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 108)
    - Helicopter Crash (700 block Yuma Street, SE), 1979 June 7 (Item 109)
    - Riot aftermath - House Office Buildings (Independence Avenue), April 1968 (Item 110)
      Aerial view of the House Office Buildings and the Capitol, view looking northwest - Smoke filled sky (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - DC Skyline (Northwest and Southwest), April 1968 (Item 111)
      Aerial view of the District, looking toward Old Post Office tower from the south (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - National Guard (F Street), April 1968 (Item 112)
      View of two National Guardsmen on patrol on F Street (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - D. J. Kaufman store (Corner of 14th and I Streets), April 1968 (Item 113)
      The burnt out shell of D. J. Kaufman store on I Street (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Military Police (Corner of 12th and F Streets), April 1968 (Item 114)
      two Military Police jeeps in the intersection of 12th and F Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Yellow Awning (Corner of 10th and F Streets), April 1968 (Item 115)
      Store awning at the corner of 10th and F Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Riot aftermath - Furniture Store (711 7th Street, between G and H Streets), April 1968 (Item 116)
      Furniture Store with clearance sign in the window (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Construction Site (Corner of 7th and K Streets), April 1968 (Item 117)
      Construction site with red and yellow tulips in foreground (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Demolished Building (Corner of 7th and K Streets), April 1968 (Item 118)
      Demolished building on the northwest corner of 7th and K Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Demolished Building (Corner of 7th and K Streets), April 1968 (Item 119)
      Demolished building on the northwest corner of 7th and K Streets (Carnegie Library in background) (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Burnt out buildings (7th Street at L Street), April 1968 (Item 120)
      Burnt out buildings along 7th Street (at L Street) National Guardsman in the street (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - H. Abramson clothing store (Corner of 7th and L Streets), April 1968 (Item 121)
      Burnt out shell of H. Abramson Clothing Store on the corner of 7th and L Streets - Soldiers in the streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Cohen's clothing store (Corner of 7th and L Streets), April 1968 (Item 122)
      Burnt out shell of Cohen's clothing store on the corner of 7th and L Streets - soldiers in the streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Cohen's clothing store (Corner of 7th and L Streets), April 1968 (Item 123)
      Burnt out shell of Cohen's clothing store on the corner of 7th and L Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Cavalier Store (7th Street near L Street), April 1968 (Item 124)
      Burnt out shell of the Cavalier store and other building on 7th Street near L Street (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Demolished building (7th and M Streets), April 1968 (Item 125)
      Demolished building on the corner of 7th and M Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Riot aftermath - Demolished building (7th and M Streets), April 1968 (Item 126)
      Demolished building on the corner of 7th and M Streets - Soldier on the side walk (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - 7th Street (7th Street), April 1968 (Item 127)
      View of 7th Street, from M Street, with cranes and soldiers in the street (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Burnt out building (9th Street between L and M Streets), April 1968 (Item 128)
      View of burnt out building on 9th Street between L and M Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Boarded up liquor store (Corner of 9th and L Streets), April 1968 (Item 129)
      Soldier stand guard at boarded up liquor store on the corner of 9th and L Streets (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - National Portrait Gallery (7th Street, NW), Ca. 1970 (Item 130)
      View of the National Portrait Gallery (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Cherry Blossom (Tidal Basin), Ca. 1970 (Item 131)
      View of people walking along the tidal basin during the Cherry Blossom festival, Jefferson Memorial in background (2 copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Cavalier Store (7th Street near L Street), April 1968 (Item 132)
      Burnt out shell of the Cavalier store and other building on 7th Street near L Street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - House Office Buildings (Independence Avenue), April 1968 (Item 133)
      Aerial view of the House Office Buildings and the Capitol, view looking northwest - Smoke filled sky (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - House Office Buildings (Independence Avenue), April 1968 (Item 134)
    - Riot aftermath - Burnt out building (9th Street between M and L Streets), April 1968 (Item 135)
      View of burnt out building on 9th Street between L and M Streets (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Riot aftermath - Cohen's clothing store (Corner of 7th and L Streets), April 1968 (Item 136)
      Burnt out shell of Cohen's clothing store on the corner of 7th and L Streets - soldiers on the street (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Freedom Plaza (Pennsylvania Avenue between 13th and 14th Streets), Ca. 1980 (Item 137)
      View of Freedom Plaza taken from the top of the District Building (2 Copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Freedom Plaza (Pennsylvania Avenue between 13th and 14th streets), Ca. 1980 (Item 138)
      View of the architectural model of Freedom Plaza design (2 Copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Pennsylvania Avenue Parade (Pennsylvania Avenue at 12th street looking east), Ca. 1900 (Item 139)
      View of a parade along Pennsylvania Avenue (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Freedom Plaza (Pennsylvania Avenue between 13th and 14th Street), Ca. 1980 (Item 140)
      Workman during the instillation of Freedom Plaza (2 Copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
  - Historic Image Collection (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Freedom Plaza (Pennsylvania Avenue between 13th and 14th Street), Ca. 1980 (Item 141)
      Aerial view of the instillation of Freedom Plaza taken from atop the Marriott Hotel (4 Copies) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Blair Mansion garden, Ca. 1865 (Item 142)
      Sketch of "rebels carousing" in the garden of Blair Mansion (Photographer: B. F. Mullen (artist))
    - Buildings on Ohio Avenue (Ohio Avenue near 12th Street), undated (Item 143)
      Sketch of buildings on Ohio Avenue, with Old Post Office building in background (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. (901 G Street, NW), undated (Item 144)
      Image of a portion of the Martin Luther King, Jr. mural in the DC Public Library's central library building (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Jefferson Memorial (Tidal Basin), Ca. 1980 (Item 145)
      View of the Jefferson Memorial from across the Tidal Basin (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Kennedy Center (Kennedy Center), Ca. 1980 (Item 146)
      View of the Kennedy Center from the Potomac River at night (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Air and Space Museum (National Mall), Ca. 1980 (Item 147)
      Interior view of the Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum showing several airplanes (Photographer: Unknown)
    - National Mall (National Mall), Ca. 1980 (Item 148)
      Aerial view of the national mall looking toward the Capitol for the Washington Monument (Image not taken from the monument) (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Boat (Potomac River), Ca. 1980 (Item 149)
      Night time view of a light up boat in the Potomac River boat is shooting plums of water (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Neptune Fountain (Library of Congress, 1st Street, SE), 1963 October (Item 150)
      View of the fountain looking south (Photographer: Unknown)
    - Neptune Fountain (Library of Congress, 1st Street, SE), 1963 October (Item 151)